Register of the Arthur N. (Arthur Nichols) Young Papers, 1918-1982
Hoover Institution Archives
Arthur N. (Arthur Nichols) Young Papers,
1918-1982
66005
Young, Arthur N. (Arthur Nichols), 1890-
119 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope, 1 oversize box, 1 album box, 1 phonotape cassette (55.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diary, correspondence, reports, studies, statistical summaries, financial statements, press releases, clippings, and ephemeral publications, relating to the European financial crisis following World War I, the work of the Reparations Commission in formulating the Dawes Plan in 1924, and the economic and financial situation in China, 1929-1946
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Inter-Allied Commission for Reparations; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration; United States. Dept. of State; Finance--China; Finance--East Asia; Finance--Europe; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--Reparations; China; China--Economic conditions--1912-1949; East Asia; Europe; Germany; Germany--Economic conditions--1918-1945; United States--Foreign relations; Economists
Biographical Notes
Arthur N. Young (Arthur Nichols)
1890, Nov. 21 Born, Los Angeles, California
1910 A.B., Occidental College
1937 LL.D., Occidental College
1911 A.M., Princeton University
1914 Ph.D., Princeton University
1927 LL.B., George Washington University
1915 Married Ellen May Bailey
1912-13 Professor of Economics, Presbyterian College, Clinton, South Carolina
1915-17 Instructor of Economics, Princeton University
1916 Author, The Single Tax Movement in the United States
1918 Author, Finances of the Federal District of Mexico
1918 Adviser on taxation, Mexican Government
1918 Trade expert, War Trade Board
1919 Trade Commissioner to investigate financial conditions in Spain for U.S. Department of Commerce
1919-20 Economist in office of foreign trade adviser, Department of State
1920-21 Financial adviser to Government of Honduras
1920 Author, Spanish Finance and Trade
1921-22 Financial expert, Department of State
1922-28 Economic adviser, Department of State
1924 Associate of American observer with Reparations Commission, Paris, during preparation of Dawes Plan
1924-26 Chairman, Interdepartmental Committee on Oil Pollution of Navigable Waters
1926 Delegate to International Conference on Oil Pollution, Washington, D.C.
1927 Expert attending World Economic Conference, Geneva
1929 Expert on public credit, Commission of Financial Experts of Chinese Government
1929-46 Financial adviser Chinese Government and Central Bank of China
1931 Member, Chinese Flood Relief Commission
1933 Expert, Chinese Economic Mission, Washington, D.C.
1936 Member of committee on establishment of Central Reserve Bank
1937-45 Director, China National Aviation Corporation
1940 Vice-president, Chinese-American Institute of Cultural Relations
1942 Vice-chairman, United China Relief Coordinating Committee
1943 Chairman, American Relief and Red Cross in China
1944 Trustee, China Foundation
1944 Adviser, Chinese Government Commission of Relief and Rehabilitation
1944 Member of Chinese delegation to Bretton Woods Financial Conference
1947 Author, China's Economic and Financial Reconstruction
1953 Author, Saudi Arabian Currency and Finance
1951-52 Director, Point IV program in Saudi Arabia and financial adviser to Saudi Arabia
1957-58 Financial Consultant, International Cooperation Administration
1958-59 Lecturer, Occidental College
1962-63 Consultant on taxation in Argentina
1971 Author, China's Nation-Building Effort, 1927-37; The Financial and Economic Record
Collection Contents
- Reparations and the Reparations Commission, 1918-1934. (Box 1-6)
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda, and printed matter collected by A.N. Young during and after his participation in the Paris Reparations Commission of 1924.
  - Diary, 1923-1924. (Box 1.)
  - Reparations, 1918-1922.
  - Reparations, 1923.
  - Dawes' Plan. Letters and Memoranda.
  - Reparation developments after Dawes' Plan, 1924. Memoranda, letters and communiques.
  - Reparations: newspaper clippings and articles, 1922-1928.
  - Reparations: newspaper clippings, 1929-1932.
  - American Army costs, 1923-1924. (Box 2.)
  - United States claim on Germany, 1924-1928.
  - Dawes' Plan. Memoranda, 1924.
  - Dawes' Plan. Reports of the reparation commission, 1924-1926.
  - Germany. Labor wages and unemployment, 1923-1924.
  - German food situation, 1924.
  - German food situation, 1923-1924.
  - German health conditions, 1923.
  - Germany. Economic situation, 1924.
  - Political attitude of leading German newspaper.
  - German loans in the United States, 1925-1927. (Box 3.)
  - Transfer problems, 1924-1927.
  - Revaluation of German currency and obligations, 1925-1926.
  - German budget, 1924-1925.
  - German currency and banking, 1923-1924.
  - Dutch-German credit agreement, 1920, 1924.
  - French finances, 1923-1924. (Box 4.)
  - French occupation of the Ruhr, 1924-1925.
  - Lecture given by A.N. Young on reparation problems, June 1925.
  - German dyes and reparations, 1924.
  - Treaty changes on Germany, 1924-1925.
  - War debts. Belgium, 1924-1925. (Box 5.)
  - War debts. United States and British matters, 1921-1927.
  - War debts. Greece, 1926-1927.
  - War debts. Italy, 1924-1927.
  - War debts. Turkey, 1927.
  - War debts. Yugoslavia, 1924-1926.
  - United States war debts. Official reports on settlements, 1921-1928.
  - Reparations. Austria
  - Financial rehabilitation Hungary, 1923-1924.
  - War debts, finances, Czechoslovakia.
  - War debts. France, 1925-1927. (Box 6.)
  - War debts. Private and official views, 1923-1928.
  - War debts. Miscellaneous, 1921-1927.
  - War debts. Newspaper clippings, 1932-1934.
- Office Files of the Financial Adviser to the Government of China, 1929-1946. (Box 7-106)
  Correspondence, reports, studies, statistical summaries, financial statements, press releases, news clippings, and ephemeral publications related to the economic and financial situation in China and acquired by A.N. Young as the financial adviser. Arranged in two subseries, the office files for the period 1929-1937 (boxes 7-61) and the office files for the period 1937-1946 (boxes 62-106).
  - Debts, general and statistics, 1931-37. (Box 7-10.)
  - Boxer Indemnity, 1929-1937. (Box 11.)
  - Customs-secured foreign loans, 1931-37. (Box 12-13.)
  - Salt secured debt, 1928-37.
  - Salt secured debt, 1928-37. (Box 14.)
  - Domestic loans secured on Boxer Indemnity, 1926-37.
  - Domestic loans secured on customs, 1926-37. (Box 15.)
  - Domestic loans secured on other than customs.
  - Domestic loans secured on other than customs. (Box 16.)
  - Consolidation, internal loans, 1929-37.
  - Consolidation, internal loans, 1929-37. (Box 17.)
  - Debts, claims of chief countries for debts in arrears, 1930-37.
  - Debts, claims of chief countries for debts in arrears, 1930-37. (Box 18.)
  - Efforts for a general debt settlement, 1925-31.
  - Efforts for a general debt settlement, 1925-31. (Box 19.)
  - Debt settlements, Finance Ministry (including Tsin-Pu and Hukuang loan issues), 1934-37. (Box 20-23.)
  - Unsettled foreign debts, 1937 (Box 24.)
  - Internal debts in arrears, 1933-37.
  - Internal debts in arrears, 1933-37. (Box 25.)
    Includes Chinese American Banc of Commerce
  - Railway dept
  - Railway debt, general, 1929-37, 1945. (Box 26.)
  - Individual railways and their debts, 1929-37. (Box 27.)
  - Individual railways and their debts, 1929-37. (Box 28.)
  - Railways, Manchuria, 1935.
  - Communications (except railways), debts and agreements, 1929-37.
  - Communications, debts and agreements, 1929-37. (Box 29.)
  - Customs, general, 1929-37.
  - Customs, general, 1929-37. (Box 30.)
  - Customs collection in gold, 1929-37. (Box 31.)
  - Manchurian customs, 1931-33.
  - Salt revenue, general, 1929-37. (Box 32.)
  - Salt revenue, Manchuria, 1931-33.
  - Salt revenue, Manchuria, 1931-33. (Box 33.)
  - Internal taxation, except salt, 1928-37.
  - Budget, 1928-37. (Box 34.)
  - Roads, shipping, telecommunications, aviation, 1929-37. (Box 35.)
  - Roads, shipping, telecommunications, aviation, 1929-37. (Box 36.)
  - China, government and political, 1929-37.
  - China, government and political, 1929-37. (Box 37.)
  - Reports on China's debt:
    - Memo on China's obligation under charge of Ministry of Railways, by Arthur N. Young. Oct. 1937., 17pp.
    - China's Obligations under Charge of the Ministries of Railways and Communications, etc., by Arthur N. Young. Aug. 1937., 78pp.
  - Annual Reports of the Ministry of Finance of Republic of China, 1928-29, 1929-30, 1930-32, 1932-34. (Box 38.)
  - Reports on China's debt. By Arthur N. Young. 1945.
  - Silver, statistics, 1934-37.
  - Silver and currency, general, 1929-36. (Box 39-40.)
  - Copper coins, 1929-35. (Box 41.)
  - Note issue, 1935-37.
  - Regional currencies, 1929-37.
  - Gold, 1930-35. (Box 42.)
  - Currency reform of 1935-37.
  - Currency reform of 1935-37. (Box 43.)
  - Currency, international negotiations, Nov. 1935 to July 1936. (Box 44.)
  - Currency policy, memos, 1930-35. (Box 45.)
  - Banking, 1930-37.
  - Central Bank, 1934-35.
  - Central Bank, 1934-35. (Box 46.)
  - Central Reserve Bank project, 1936-37. (Box 47.)
  - Coinage and mint, 1929-37.
  - Coinage and mint, 1929-37. (Box 48.)
  - Prices, including published price indexes and reports, 1929-37.
  - Prices. (Box 49.)
  - Prices. (Box 50.)
  - Data prepared for Leith-Ross, 1935.
  - Finance, general, 1929-37. (Box 51.)
  - Finance, general, 1929-37. (Box 52.)
  - Economic development, reconstruction and planning, education, patents, treaties, 1930-37.
  - Economic development, 1930-37. (Box 53.)
  - Japan and China, clippings, printed matter, press releases, 1930-37.
  - Japan and China, 1930-37. (Box 54.)
  - Japan and China, 1930-37. (Box 55.)
  - Flood relief, 1931.
  - Flood relief, 1931. (Box 56.)
  - Commodity loan negotiations, 1932-33. (Box 57.)
  - Cotton and wheat loan, 1931-36.
  - Cotton and wheat loan, 1931-36. (Box 58-60.)
  - Cotton and wheat loan, 1931-36. (Box 61.)
  - Posters (three)
- Office Files of the Financial Adviser to the Government of China, 1937-1946.
  - Prices. Kunming-Chungking Farmers' Bank. Various cities, 1937-45. (Box 62.)
  - European inflation, 1914-1925.
  - Prices. Shanghai, 1937-45. (Box 63.)
  - Prices. Shanghai, 1945-46.
  - CRB October 1945-46.
  - China Weekly Review August 1926 (daily translation service).
  - Economic Weekly, University of Nanking, April 3, 1947 - September 23, 1948.
  - Financial price statistics - 1947-48; wholesale prices in Shanghai 1948.
  - Princes in Peiping 1947-48.
  - Fortnightly letter, etc., December 1, 1945. (Box 64.)
  - Central Bank of China - Daily reports. December 1945-July 1946. Weekly reports, financial statements.
  - Central Bank of China - Daily reports and financial statements, September 1946-November 1947. (Box 65.)
  - Daily reports and financial statements, November-December 1947. (Box 66.)
  - Economic News Bulletin, March-June 1946.
  - Economic News Bulletin, June-August 1946. (Box 67.)
  - Telegrams, Rogers, Pei, January-December 1939. (Box 68.)
  - Central Bank of China, statements, 1938-40.
  - Currency, January-June 1939.
  - Import and export papers, July 1939.
  - Currency, July-August 1939.
  - Currency, September-December 1939.
  - Currency, January-June 1940.
  - Currency, June-December 1940. (Box 69.)
  - Currency, January-May 1941.
  - Currency, June-December 1941.
  - Exchange control, 1940-41.
  - Finance Ministry's exchange allotments, 1940.
  - Exchange banking, July 1937-March 1938.
  - Telegrams, Rogers and Pei, 1940.
  - Allotments, 1938. (Box 70.)
  - Currency, 1938.
  - Import and exchange registrations, 1938.
  - Operation of Mandate, March 12, 1938.
  - Hankow currency exchange, early 1938.
  - Central Bank reserves, mid 1937-August 1939.
  - Correspondence, telegrams, conference notes, 1940-41. (Box 71.)
  - Telegrams, letters, Rogers and Pei, 1938-January 4, 1939.
  - Stabilization Fund, July-November 1941.
  - Stabilization Fund, 1942-46.
  - Exchange allotments, 1938-39.
  - Currency, June-December 1938.
  - Telegrams, Rogers and Pei, 1941. (Box 72.)
  - United States, freezing and control, 1940.
  - Kunming, Chengtu (documents, correspondence, statistical reports), 1939-44.
  - Stabilization agreements, 1941.
  - Trade controls-stabilization, August 1941.
  - British and Hongkong exchange registrations, 1941.
  - Customs, 1939. (Box 73.)
  - Customs, 1939-1940.
  - Customs, 8 December 1941-1942.
  - Customs, 1943.
  - Customs, 1944-15 August 1945.
  - Customs, 1945-1947.
  - Treasury law, 1938-1942. Customs and salt.
  - Trade control, 1938.
  - China and American Trade Council, 1944-1945.
  - Foreign trade, 1937-1945.
  - Export and import, 1937-1945.
  - Miscellaneous, 1937-1938.
  - Miscellaneous, 1939.
  - Salt, January-June 1938. (Box 74.)
  - Salt, July-December 1938.
  - Salt, 1939.
  - Salt, 1940-1941.
  - Salt, 1941.
  - Salt, 1942-1944.
  - United States - Japan trade embargo, 1939.
  - Trade controls, 1945-1946.
  - Land tax figures, various dates.
  - Taxes, 1937-1941.
  - Land taxes, 1941-1945.
  - Taxation, 1942.
  - Customs, August 1937-31 December 1937. (Box 75.)
  - Customs and Anglo-Japanese Customs Agreement, January-April 1938.
  - Anglo-Japanese Agreement, 29 April-31 May 1938.
  - Miscellaneous, 1940.
  - Miscellaneous, 1941.
  - Miscellaneous, 1942.
  - Miscellaneous, 1943.
  - Miscellaneous, 1944.
  - Miscellaneous, 1945.
  - Budget figures, mid-1937 to mid-1944. (Box 76.)
  - Budget (miscellaneous), 1938-1944.
  - Budget data, 1945-1946.
  - Anglo-Japanese customs agency, 11 June 1938-31 December 1938.
  - Customs (miscellaneous), 1938.
  - Taxation, 1944-1946.
  - Price controls, 1937-1945. (Box 77.)
  - Princes, Chengtu, 1937-1945.
  - Prices, 1940.
  - Prices, 1941.
  - Prices, 1942.
  - Prices, 1943-1944.
  - Prices, 1944-1945.
  - Exchange rates.
  - Market reports, 1940.
  - Market reports to 30 June 1941.
  - International Monetary Fund, telegrams 1943-1944. (Box 78.)
  - International Monetary Fund, 1943 - 1 June 1943.
  - International Monetary Fund, 1 June 1943.
  - International Monetary Fund, 1944.
  - International Monetary Fund, 15 June 1944 - 15 August 1945.
  - Market reports, 1938. (Box 79.)
  - Market reports, 1939.
  - North China currency, 1937-1938.
  - North China currency, 1939.
  - North China currency, 1940-1941.
  - Central Reserve Bank, Shanghai, 1940-1941.
  - Hua-Hsing Bank, 1939-1941.
  - Puppet currency.
  - Puppet currency, 1942-1945.
  - Banking, 1943-1946.
  - Nelson-war production and inflation, 1944-1945.
  - South China currency, 1937-1939. (Box 80.)
  - Currency, 1942.
  - Currency, 1943.
  - Currency, 1944.
  - Currency, 1945-15 August 1945.
  - National Aid Council, 1943-1945. (Box 81.)
  - National Aid Council, 1945-1946.
  - Reconstruction and development, 1942-1944.
  - Reconstruction programs, August 1945.
  - Reconstruction programs, November 1945.
  - Unidentified correspondence, reports, etc., 1942-1949.
  - UNRRA papers, May - June 1944. (Box 82.)
  - UNRRA report, July - December 1944.
  - UNRRA, 1945-15 August 1945.
  - UNRRA, 1945-1946.
  - UNRRA - China's ability to pay, 1945.
  - UNRRA documents, May - August 1946.
  - CNRRA, June 1946.
  - UNRRA relief, 1947.
  - Developments, March 1946. (Box 83.)
  - Relief and rehabilitation, 1943.
  - Relief and rehabilitation (miscellaneous), January - June 1944.
  - Relief, UCR 1944.
  - Relief, UCR 1945.
  - UCR, American Advisory Committee, private relief.
  - Planning for post war. General, 1941-1943. (Box 84.)
  - Planning for post war. General, 1944.
  - Planning for post war. General, 1945.
  - Foreign capital investments, 1943-1945.
  - Foreign banks in China, 1944-1945.
  - International banks to 15 June 1944.
  - International banks from 15 June 1944 to 1947.
  - Chinese industrial cooperatives. (Box 85.)
  - International Food Conference, 1943.
  - Insurance, 1943-1945.
  - Gold, 1937-1939.
  - Gold, 1942.
  - Gold, 1943.
  - Gold, 1944.
  - Gold, 1943-1945.
  - Gold, 1945.
  - Debts, memoranda, China. (Box 86.)
  - Wartime internal debt, regulations and figures, 1937-1943.
  - Joint office of four government banks, authorized loans, 1943-1946.
  - Boxer indemnity, 1937-1945 (China Foundation).
  - Boxer indemnity from 1945 (China Foundation).
  - Liberty loans, 1937. (Box 87.)
  - Internal foreign currency debts, 1938-1945.
  - Internal borrowings from the public in National Chinese dollars, 1943-1944.
  - Chinese News Service, 1947-1949.
  - Russian aid, 1937-1945. (Box 88.)
  - French-Belgian loans, 1937-1941.
  - Britain-purchase credits of 1938-1941.
  - K.P. Chen's mission to the United States 1938.
  - K.P. Chen's mission to the United States, 1939-1940.
  - T.V. Soong's mission, 1940-1941.
  - United States $500 million loan, 1942-1945.
  - Foreign loans, post war period.
  - Report by A.N. Young dated February 1934 and memorandum by Arthur Young dated October 1937. (Box 89.)
  - Financing China Invasion. Report by A.N. Young submitted to John McCloy, Assistant Secretary of War, 21 October 1944.
  - Foreign loans, July 1937 - June 1938.
  - Extended assets and their use, 1938-1945.
  - British loans, 1942-1945.
  - United States bond scheme, to issuance, 1941-1942.
  - United States securities, from issuance 1942 to August 1943.
  - Japanese cost of war in China, correspondence and charts.
  - United States army and navy costs in China. Reverse lend-lease. Miscellaneous military matters.
  - United States savings certificates, 1943-1946.
  - United States lend-lease, 1941.
  - United States lend-lease, 1941.
  - Lend-lease (United States and Britain) after 1941.
  - Debt moratorium, 1938 to 31 January 1939. (Box 90.)
  - Debt moratorium and negotiations from 1 February 1939.
  - Debt figures (miscellaneous), 1937-1945.
  - Debt quotations, 1939-1945.
  - Debt in arrears, 1943-1946.
  - Foreign debts (miscellaneous), June 1939 - June 1940.
  - Foreign debts (miscellaneous), June 1940 - December 1941.
  - Enemy seized bonds, 1942.
  - Looted securities.
  - Finance Ministry reports, 1929-1935. (Box 91.)
  - Debt memos (China) for Stanford University Library.
  - Memoranda and reports by A.N. Young, June and July 1945, January and July 1937.
  - Exchange rates, United States dollars, quotations, 1945-1948.
  - Gold, 1945-1947.
  - Silver, 1944-1947.
  - Hong Kong - Macao, 1947.
  - Financial controls, miscellaneous.
  - Foreign loans, miscellaneous, July - December 1938.
  - Balance of payments, 1947. (Box 92.)
  - Balance of payments, 1947-1949.
  - International Monetary Fund, 1947. Documents.
  - Revenues and expenditures, 1945-1947. Miscellaneous.
  - Banking land, etc., 1946.
  - Banking, 1945-1946.
  - Bretton Woods Conference. General post war fund.
  - Budget 1946-current data.
  - Trade and trade control. (Box 93.)
  - Trade and trade control, 1947.
  - Cotton credit, 1946.
  - Cotton credit, 1947.
  - Foreign credits to China (except cotton), 1946.
  - Military aid to China. Military matters, 1945-1947.
  - Economic conditions, 1945-1947.
  - Political and miscellaneous material, post war.
  - United States post war aid. (Box 94.)
  - Private debts, 1945-1947.
  - Profits tax, 1947.
  - Surplus property, 1946.
  - Surplus property (lend-lease), 1947.
  - Shanghai stock exchange, 1945-1946.
  - Shanghai Power Company, 1945-1947.
  - Trade, 1 June 1946-31 December 1946.
  - Supply of money, 1946. (Box 95.)
  - Currency, 1 September 1946 to 1947.
  - Currency, 1947.
  - Currency, 1948-1949.
  - Foreign Exchange Equalizations and Fund Committee.
  - Foreign Exchange Equalization Fund Report, 31 December 1947.
  - Daily notes on meetings.
  - Daily market reports, 1947.
  - Market operations, December 1947 - June 1948.
  - Exchange operations, 1947-1948.
  - Exchange operations, March - June 1948.
  - Exchange regulations and orders, 1947.
  - Weekly report of foreign exchange. (Box 96.)
  - Statement showing foreign exchange purchases.
  - Unauthorized imports.
  - Exchange Equalization Fund accounts.
  - Daily fund rates.
  - Reports from Bank of Canton, Hong Kong.
  - Exchange bought 1947.
  - Currency, 15 August 1945 - 31 December 1945. (Box 97.)
  - North China. Post-war currency.
  - Exchange control, 1946.
  - Forms.
  - Regulation forms for exchange control, February 1946.
  - Brokers, 1946.
  - Exchange control circulars, 2 March - 12 August 1946.
  - Applications and cases.
  - Old papers regarding plans enforcing exchange, early 1946.
  - Press comments on currency, 1946.
  - Control Bank, 1 January - 6 August 1946.
  - United States $500 million reserve, 1946.
  - Foreign currency; exchange position, 1946.
  - Miscellaneous material from Cyril Rogers, Central Bank of China, 1947-1948. (Box 98.)
  - Notes, 1945 and 1947.
  - Notes, 1948 and 1949.
  - Blocked funds. Chinese private assets abroad, to 1947.
  - Needs and sources of exchange, 1945.
  - Needs and sources of exchange, 1946-1947.
  - Foreign currency positions, 1947-1948.
  - Prices, 1946.
  - Prices, 1947-1948.
  - Clippings, statements, correspondence on United States economic embargo against Japan, including correspondence with The American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression, 1939-1941. (Box 99.)
  - China Air Mail, by Gunther Stein, 1939-1941.
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings on China, 1944-1949 (collected by Allen Young).
  - Japan and China, press clippings, 21 July to 10 August 1937. (Box 100.)
  - Japan and China, press clippings, 21 August to 5 September 1937.
  - Japan and China, press clippings, 6 September to 23 September 1937.
  - Japan and China, press clippings, 24 September to 7 October 1937.
  - Japan and China, press clippings, 8 October to 31 October 1937.
  - Japan and China, press clippings, 1939 (Allen Young). (Box 101.)
  - Japan and China, press clippings, 1939-1940.
  - News and press releases, 1937-1938.
  - North China, clippings and statements, 7 July 1937 to 20 July 1937.
  - Miscellaneous leaflets, pamphlets and publications relating to China.
  - Newspaper clippings, July - December 1940. (Box 102.)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1941.
  - Newspaper clippings, Japan and China, 1940-1941.
  - CNAC statements, 1939-1940. (Box 103.)
  - CNAC, Chungking file, 1938-1940.
  - CNAC, Chungking file, 1941.
  - CNAC aviation, 1 January to 30 July 1943.
  - CNAC aviation, 1 July to 31 December 1942.
  - CNAC aviation, 1 January to 30 June 1943. (Box 104.)
  - CNAC aviaiton, 1 July to 31 December 1943.
  - CNAC aviation, 1944.
  - CNAC (miscellaneous), 1941-1945.
  - Burma Road, Indo-China Route, 1938. (Box 105.)
  - Burma Road, Indo-China Route, 1939.
  - Burma Road, Indo-China Route, 1940.
  - Burma Road, Indo-China Route, January - June 1941.
  - Burma Road, Indo-China Route, June - July 1941.
  - Burma Road, Indo-China Route, August 1941.
  - Burma-China Railway, 1938-1941.
  - Air routes, Burma-India, 1939-1941.
  - Import goods by air and Stilwell road, 1943-1945.
  - Aviation-military, 1939-1941.
  - Military (miscellaneous), 1941.
  - Aviation Consolidation Trade Company, 1939. (Box 106.)
  - Propos[UNK]ed aviation school, 1940.
  - Aviation, civil, 1940 (Washington file).
  - Aviation, civil, 1 January - 31 May 1941 (Washington file).
  - Aviation, Flying Tigers, 1940-1941.
  - Communications (miscellaneous), 1945-1946.
  - Aviation (miscellaneous), 1947.
  - Water transport, 1944-1946.